# Joseph John Spall IV

323 Old Bailey Lane, West Chester, PA 19382

Phone: (302) 598-4085 | E-Mail: jspall0327@gmail.com | GitHub: jspall0327 | United States Citizen

#### **Objective**

I am seeking an internship during the summer of 2020 in the field of embedded systems or firmware. With my two years of work experience on projects in the robotics and automation industry, I believe I can make a considerable contribution to your company on both the technical and non-technical front.

#### Education

#### Georgia Institute of Technology, Atlanta, Georgia

August 2016 - Present

- Bachelor of Science in Electrical Engineering, Minoring in Robotics, GPA 3.85/4.00
- Expected graduation in May of 2021

#### **Experience**

## Factory Automation Systems, Atlanta, Georgia Electrical Engineering Co-op

**January 2018 – August 2019** 

- Designed multiple industrial automated control systems for major manufacturing companies
- Evaluated electrical and software assemblies before being shipped to clients
- Wrote Rockwell Ladder Logic for alarm handling and process control to function with GE Cimplicity Human-Machine Interface System

# OneMain Financial, Wilmington, Delaware Risk Analytics Intern

May - August 2016, 2017

- Compiled a 7,000 line, server-backed JavaFX application for teaching loan evaluation skills to new and experienced employees, being used at over 2,200 locations
- Created a Chrome Extension to cycle through URLs for use on 5 corporate display screens
- Assisted with testing and refining new risk strategies using SAS and Excel

## Spallco Car and Truck Rentals, Newark, Delaware Operations Assistant

June - August, 2012 to 2015

- Detailed vehicles after customer use
- Assisted with vehicle availability with prompt detailing and condition assessment
- Maintained over 150 vehicles in the fleet between 3 offices to interface with inventory management

#### **Leadership**

#### **RoboJackets**

September 2016 - Present

#### President

- Manages over 270 dues-paving members across 5 different competition robotics teams
- Generated and taught introductory electrical engineering curriculum to over 50 new students
- Designed and assembled 2 custom fleets of 15 robots for teaching new members C++

#### Lighthouse

October 2016 – December 2017

#### Project Leader / Co-Creator

- Compiled over 3,200,000 crime entries from Atlanta, New York City, Chicago, Philadelphia, and Los Angeles to determine safer walking routes in each city
- Developed a mobile safety app for iOS and Android with a MongoDB backend server
- Presented at the Fall 2017 Georgia Tech CREATE-X project fair

#### Skills

- *Programming:* C++, PLC Ladder Logic, Swift, MATLAB, Java, Python
- Hardware: circuit design, soldering, circuit production, Arduino, mbed, embedded systems
- Software: EAGLE, RSLogix, EPLAN Electric P8, AutoCAD, GitHub

#### **Awards / Interests**

- Awards: Archmere Computer Science Award, Verizon Innovative App Challenge Best in State, New Castle County Intel Science Fair 2nd Place, 2016 GT Datathon 1st Place, 2017 HackGT Memea-thon 1st Place, 2017 IARRC 3rd place, 2017 Sparkfun AVC 1st Place, 2018 Sparkfun AVC 1st Place, 2019 IARRC 1st place
- Interests: Competition robotics, ultimate frisbee, hackathons, casual programming projects